the key to any great home gym is finding
yourself a solid centerpiece and due to
the versatility a power rack is
typically the way to go however they
tend to dominate almost too much space
now you could always go down you know
the photable Rack Route but if you're
not wanting to actually bolt a rack into
your walls then you definitely want to
Target something that's pretty compact
one of my personal favorite options is
the bells of Steel Hydra rack this is a
fully customizable power rack so you're
able to make it meet your exact needs
whether that be a behemoth of Iraq or as
compact as possible like I have right
here behind me there's a whole lot to
talk about today in this video so let's
just get right to
[Music]
[Applause]
it what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the Barb and garage gym and for today's
video I'm going to be breaking down the
bells of Steel Hydra Rack in this video
today I'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about it from the price
some pros and cons the features and of
course who should or maybe should not
make this purchase but before I do that
if you don't already know we've reviewed
a whole lot of other power acts from
bbbind.com and guess what we have a best
list of all of our top picks so if you
want to check that out all you got to do
is search barbend best power ax it's
going to pull right up for you and you
can find out for yourself which one
cracks that number one spot
[Music]
okay so I think the first thing we got
to talk about when it comes to the pros
is just the customization process
there's so many different configurations
you can do with this rack it's almost
overwhelming so you can customize the
height the width and the depth of it so
I have the smallest configuration
possible right now I just kind of wanted
to do that just to show you guys you
know if you're tight on Space it's a lot
of you know people's issues with home
gems isace space so if you're tight on
space this is like one of my favorite
options out there might even be the best
overall option which is pretty cool
these uprights are true 3x3 in 11 gauge
seal so 11 gauge steel you know it's the
highest quality you could ask for with a
power rack really with any gym equipment
in general so it's going to have an
1100b weight capacity but that true 3x3
in what I mean by that is you know a lot
of other racks out there you know rep
and some other companies they claim 3x3
in but it's actually just a shade under
so you know the fact this is 3x3 there a
little bit more steel involved it's a
little bit higher quality it's going to
be really nice it's going to be durable
and just lasts you a long time which is
something that you definitely want you
do have Westside spacing so Westside
spacing where these you know holes right
here are one inch apart so that's really
nice it's going to be really helpful
especially when you're going to bench
press you know it's going to allow you
to get that perfect fit you know for
your arm length and everything like that
so that's pretty cool as well remember
there's a ton of attachments so we're
going to talk about it all a second but
you can literally fully kit this thing
out and you're not going to have really
you know anything you're lacking in your
home gym which is just amazing now you
need to be aware of the price tag so the
cheapest this is going to be is pretty
much the rack that I built right here
it's going to be around 900 bucks or so
but you can easily spend over well over
five grand with all the attachments
included which I'll kind of detail in
just a minute just kind of keep that in
mind now the building process for me was
also pretty easy because this is the
smallest version of the rack but
depending on your specific configuration
could take you hours on end and you
might need you at least one extra set of
hands and then I've had you know kind of
some issues actually you know a pretty
big issue with getting the actual you
know compatible attachments delivered to
me there's been a couple times now where
they've sent the wrong stuff that
happens to me might happen to you as
well so just kind of remember that
whenever you're going to make this
purchase
okay so I already touched on it a little
bit but remember the pricing for this
Hydra rack really just depends on your
specific configuration and you know when
you compare to you know other companies
out there there's obviously tons and
tons of power racks right so for me the
best direct comparison is with rep
Fitness with the pr 4000 and the pr 5000
because they also have a rack Builder
feature where you customize everything
color height width ATT Ms everything
right so once again you know with the
hydro rack it's going to start around
$900 or so for you know the most basic
smallest rack and it could easily be
over five grand you know the bigger it
is the more steel involved and the more
expensive the actual rack becomes but
then also you you got to tack on all the
attachments and everything like that as
well so yeah it could be really
expensive but the luxury of having you
know a customizable rack is just the
fact that you know you can tailor it to
you know your available space in your
home gym but also your specific budget
which honestly is a pretty sweet
[Music]
thing so once again with the Hydra Rack
you're working with 3x3 in 11 gauge
steel uprights really durable really
high quality highest quality you could
ask for and it's going to lead to that
1000lb weight capacity which is going to
suffice the needs of 99% of home gym
athletes which is really cool now it is
it does have a powder coat finish I have
the black one it's also available in
blue and purple when it comes to the
customization process this is my
favorite part it's the main selling
point with this rack you have four
different heights to choose from three
different depths and then two different
widths you can work with as well that
way you're able to you know either pick
one that takes up a whole lot of space
or if you don't have a lot of space make
it as compact as possible which is a
great thing the attachments the
attachments are awesome there're so many
to choose from whether you just looking
for you know your style of safeties to a
dip attachment land mine attachment even
a leg curl leg extension there's so many
different ones for you to choose from so
with all these you know possibilities
with the attachments aside from your
free weights this could literally be the
only piece of equipment that you need in
your home
[Music]
gym okay so remember you do have your
3x3 in 11 gauge steel uprights right
here and this is a powder coat out have
the black one obviously remember it's
blue and purple as well now I haven't
used this a whole lot I've had it for
just a couple weeks now so I haven't had
really you know any scratches show up
but with a powder coat it is going to
happen I have the pr 5000 right over
there and had that for almost a year now
right around a year and there's plenty
of scratches and stuff on that it's just
normal wear and tear nothing you can do
about it now these J cups pretty basic
but you do have that plastic right here
it's going to protect your barbell
definitely gets the job done now my
pull-up bar right here is also very
basic but that's because of the build
that I have if if you go for the 43 in
wide build then you're going to be able
to have the option of a globe grip
multi-grip there's I think five
different ones you can choose from so
just definitely you know keep that in
mind now this is also 72 in tall I went
with the smallest one on purpose just to
show you guys you know how compact you
really can get this also this is 24 in
right here so this is literally the
smallest build that they have if you're
short on you know ceiling height or
anything like that this is an amazing
fit for you literally an amazing fit for
you now I also have these safety straps
this is what I went with unfortunately
the connectors that go here and connect
you know to the uprights they didn't
send the right ones so those are going
to be on the way and I'll be able to
update our article remember barbin bells
of Steel Hydra review definitely go
check that out so I'll be able to update
that with my experience over time but
basically you know these are just going
to go in here and the reason I went with
these is because they're not going to
damage my barbell if I fail a lift and I
have to drop it whatever this is is
going to be really great for that I do
have my barbell holder on the back right
here it's nice you know it kind of saves
you some space a little bit and that's
really cool but remember there's so many
different attachments that can just go
everywhere here can almost look like a
spaceship it can get a little bit
overwhelming now because I have the
smallest rack it's the lightest rack
which is a good thing because you can
move it around if you want to switch up
the funu of your home gym but because of
that you have to worry about the
possibility of it tipping so my barbell
is kind of you know preventing that a
little bit right now but I can easily
you know pull that down if I want to so
putting heavy weight out here on the
back of the Rack or the front of the
rack excuse me might not be you know the
most ideal situation definitely keep
that in mind but if you're worried about
that whatsoever you do have the option
of bolting the rack there's you know
little bolt spot here and there and it's
same thing on the back right there as
well so if you go and do that then
that's something you won't have to worry
about at all and once again you can put
up to 1,000 lb on this rack and it's not
going to tip over all right so I think
pretty much everybody could benefit by
you know having this rack the
customization process is literally
endless you can have as many attachments
as you want or you can go as basic as
you want and plus you have that 11 gauge
steel build with that true 3x3 in
upright so it's going to be durable it's
going to last you a really long time and
it has that high weight capacity so if
you're you know an elite lifter it's
still going to work you know it's still
going meet you your strength
requirements only thing I think you got
to worry about is still just the money I
mean the cheapest this rack is going to
be it's still floating around
$900 and you know at that point if
you're just going for the you know basic
version of the rack unless you're just
really wanting that 11 gauge steel you
can find some $400 racks out there one
in particular is the rep pr100 which is
under
[Music]
$400 that's all I got for youall today
on the bells of Steel Hydra rack this is
one of my favorite racks on the market
there's so many customizations you can
work with that way you can make it fit
in your designated space but then also
work within your budget as well and
don't forget it does have that really
durable 11 gauge steel build thanks for
watching y'all hope this video was
really helpful and I was able to detail
everything there is to know about this
rack as always stay posted for my next
video but for now head over to barb.
comom cuz we have a full written article
about this rack that I definitely think
you should check out all you got to do
is search barbin bells of Steel Hydro
rack review and it's going to pull right
up for you you can read over everything
that we talked about here today I'll
catch youall next
[Music]
time